question_data = {
	
	questions: [
	
	// EXAM 2013
	
		{
			"question": "You just read about a study showing a positive relation between the share of beer in total alcohol consumption and traffic fatalities and you know that wine and beer are substitutes. Based on this information, you may conclude",
			"correct_answer": "None of the one mentioned",
			"wrong_answers": ["that wine consumption lower traffic fatalities", "that beer consumption raises traffic fatalities", "that wine is taxed too much from a public policy point of view", "All of the one mentioned"]
		},
	
	
		{
			"question": "Which of the following would you include as explanatory variable when estimating a wine demand function for Italy",
			"correct_answer": "Per capita income",
			"wrong_answers": ["Wine Quality Ratings", "Regional Origin", "Wine Age", "Rießling"]
		},

		{
			"question": "Which of the following wine varieties is not a CORE variety in Alto Adige (South Tyrol)?",
			"correct_answer": "Chardonnay",
			"wrong_answers": ["Lagrein", "Gewürztraminer", "Pinot Noir", "All of the one mentioned are core varieties in Alto Adige"]
		},
		{
			"question": "Which statement is incorrect if your estimated model is given by Price = 6.5 + 0.12*(temperature) + 0.05*(sunshine) - 0.025*(rainfall)",
			"correct_answer": "All of the one mentioned exept 'More sunshine will cause the price to increase'",
			"wrong_answers": ["An increase in sunshine hours by one unit will cause the price to increase by 5%", "An increase in rainfall by one unit will cause the price to fall by 2.5%", "More sunshine will cause the price to increase", "Sunshine is more important than rain", "All of the one mentioned exept 'Sunshine is more important than rain'"]
		},


		{
			"question": "Which of the following conditions will not contribute to wine quality?",
			"correct_answer": "None of the one mentioned",
			"wrong_answers": ["Yields", "Average hours of sunshine", "Average ranfall during growing season", "Inclination / direction of sunlight"]
		},
	

		{
			"question": "Which of the following conditions does not affect wine quality?",
			"correct_answer": "None of the one mentioned",
			"wrong_answers": ["Day and night-time temperature differences", "Rainfall during growing season", "Daytime Temperatures", "Sunshine hours"]
		},
	
		{
			"question": "Which of the following are wine quality signals to consumers?",
			"correct_answer": "All of the one mentioned",
			"wrong_answers": ["Regional origin of the wine", "IGT classification", "Parker points", "Vintage"]
		},
	
		{
			"question": "Wine consumers rely on quality signals because it is",
			"correct_answer": "time consuming and costly to search for quality information",
			"wrong_answers": ["a search good", "subject to counterfeiting", "not consumed regualrly", "a luxury good"]
		},
	
	
		{
			"question": "Wine consumers rely on quality signals because",
			"correct_answer": "All of the one mentioned exept 'wine is a search good'",
			"wrong_answers": ["wine is an experience good", "wine is a search good", "searching for information about quality is ineffective", "searching for information about quality is costly", "All of the one mentioned exept 'searching for information about quality is ineffective'"]
		},
	
	
		{
			"question": "Producer incentives to supply quality wine are no affected by",
			"correct_answer": "political regulations",
			"wrong_answers": ["the collective reputation of their growing region", "their own actions (in the past and at present)", "the actions of other producers in the region", "All of the one mentioned"]
		},
	
		{
			"question": "Not admong the classical assumptions of the linear regression model is that",
			"correct_answer": "None of the one mentioned",
			"wrong_answers": ["the stochastic error term has a zero mean", "the stochastic error term has a constant variance", "all erros are independent of one another", "all errorss are independent of the explanatory variable(s)"]
		},
	
		{
			"question": "The six key players in the global wine industry",
			"correct_answer": "All of the one mentioned except 'include an Italian company'",
			"wrong_answers": ["are less concentrated than the global beer industry", "include a company that is more known for beer", "include a privately owned company", "include an Italian company", "All of the one mentioned except 'are less concentrated than the global beer industry'"]
		},
	
	
		{
			"question": "Which of the following statements on wine trade (total quantity) is false?",
			"correct_answer": "None of the one mentioned",
			"wrong_answers": ["Germany is the leading wine importer in the world", "Germany is Italy's main export market for wine", "Australia's main export markets for wine are the USA and the UK", "Italy is the leading wine exporter in the world in terms of quantity"]
		},
	
		// 12
	
		{
			"question": "Which varieties comprise a classic Bordeaux style wine?",
			"correct_answer": "Cabernet Sauvignon, Cabernet Franc, Merlot, Petit Verdot, Malbec",
			"wrong_answers": ["Cabernet Sauvignon, Merlot, Petit Verdot, Malbec", "Cabernet Sauvignon, Cabernet Franc, Merlot, Syrah, Malbec", "Cabernet Sauvignon, Merlot, Petit Verdot", "Cabernet Sauvignon, Cabernet Franc, Merlot"]
		},
	
		{
			"question": "Identify any incorrect wine region / core variety pairing!",
			"correct_answer": "Argentina / Merlot",
			"wrong_answers": ["Australia / Shiraz", "California / Zinfandel", "Chile / Carmenere", "Tuscany / Sangiovese"]
		},
	
	
		{
			"question": "Identify any incorrect wine region / core variety pairing!",
			"correct_answer": "Chile / Tempranillo",
			"wrong_answers": ["Australia / Shiraz", "California / Zinfandel", "Argentina / Malbec", "Tuscany / Sangiovese"]
		},
	
		{
			"question": "According to the literature, it is incorrect to state that the price anomaly",
			"correct_answer": "does not exist for wine auctions",
			"wrong_answers": ["in wine auctions is explained by absentee bidders", "in wine auctions exists because of risk averse bidders", "in wine auctions is due to option value effects", "None of the one mentioned"]
		},
	
		{
			"question": "The European Union had to cope with a structural surplus of wine because",
			"correct_answer": "All of the one mentioned",
			"wrong_answers": ["the main production countries consume less", "imports increased faster than exports", "past polocies encouraged production", "past policies were ineffective"]
		},
	
		{
			"question": "Which of the following statements regarding regression(s) is/are incorrect:",
			"correct_answer": "It is not problematic if two independent variables in a regression are correlated",
			"wrong_answers": ["Ordinary least squares (OLS) estimation minimizes the sum of squared residuals", "The coefficient of determinations measures how well your model fits the data", "Ordinary least squares (OLS) allows us to estimate relationships between variables from sample data", "None of the one mentioned"]
		},
	
		// T/F
	
		{
			"question": "Crop thinning may raise the wine quality.",
			"correct_answer": "True",
			"wrong_answers": ["False"]
		},
	
		{
			"question": "Regionalismn is a distinct feature of wine markets in Europa.",
			"correct_answer": "False",
			"wrong_answers": ["True"]
		},
	
		{
			"question": "A situation in which the bidder who overestimates the value of an object wins an auction is referred as the winners curse.",
			"correct_answer": "True",
			"wrong_answers": ["False"]
		},
	
	
		// exam preperation
	
		{
			"question": "Global wine production is dominated by the 'big three'. This term comprises the following countries:",
			"correct_answer": "France, Italy and Spain",
			"wrong_answers": ["Spain, France and China", "Spain, U.S.A. and France", "France, Italy and Australia", "None of the one mentioned"]
		},
	
		{
			"question": "In terms of acreage planted, the most popular grape variety in Germany is",
			"correct_answer": "Riesling",
			"wrong_answers": ["Pinot Noir", "Müller-Thurgau",  "Chardonnay", "None of the one mentioned"]
		},
	
		{
			"question": "What determines the alcohol content in a bottle of wine?",
			"correct_answer": "the amount of sugar in the grape",
			"wrong_answers": ["the amount of yeast added to the wine", "the wine's aging process", "the type of grape (variety)", "The first letter of the country of origin"]
		},
	
		{
			"question": "You just heard of a study that links moderate red wine consumption and lower rates of heart disease. Based on this information, you expect that",
			"correct_answer": "All of the one mentioned",
			"wrong_answers": ["wine consumption increases", "wine prices increase", "demand for red wine shifts", "None of the one mentioned"]
		},
	
		// T/F Hannes Sigmund
	
		{
			"question": "In order to increase the market price of wine, the EU distilled wine and turns it into alcohol.",
			"correct_answer": "True",
			"wrong_answers": ["False"]
		},
	
		{
			"question": "The market concentration in the beer industry is greater than in the wine industry.",
			"correct_answer": "False",
			"wrong_answers": ["True"]
		},

	
		{
			"question": "Countries with low alcohol taxes generally have higher per-capita alcohol consumption.",
			"correct_answer": "True",
			"wrong_answers": ["False"]
		},
	
		// T/F Monika Hofer
	
	
		{
			"question": "The price elasticity of demand is constant along a Cobb-Douglas demand curve.",
			"correct_answer": "True",
			"wrong_answers": ["False"]
		},
	
		{
			"question": "A wine region's reputation for wine quality is constant over time.",
			"correct_answer": "False",
			"wrong_answers": ["True"]
		},

	
		{
			"question": "A situation in which the bidder who overestimates the value of and object wins an auction is referred as the winners curse.",
			"correct_answer": "True",
			"wrong_answers": ["False"]
		},
	
	
		//// SELF MADE
	
		{
			"question": "Which continent of them has the most area of vineyards?",
			"correct_answer": "Asia",
			"wrong_answers": ["America", "Africa", "Australia"]
		},
	
	
		{
			"question": "Which country had the biggest increase in vineyards between 2000 and 2014",
			"correct_answer": "China",
			"wrong_answers": ["Spain", "Italy", "France", "USA", "Chile", "Mongolia"]
		},
	
	
		{
			"question": "Which country has the 5th most area of vineyards (after Spain, China, France and Italy)?",
			"correct_answer": "Turkey",
			"wrong_answers": ["USA", "Germany", "Austria", "Argentinia", "Brasilia", "Iran", "Chile"]
		},
	
	
		{
			"question": "In which unit is the TOTAL wine production measured?",
			"correct_answer": "in millions of hectoliters",
			"wrong_answers": ["in millions of liters", "in liter", "in hectoliters", "in milliliters"]
		},
	
	
	
		{
			"question": "What was the estimated world wine production in 2015?",
			"correct_answer": "274.4 mhl",
			"wrong_answers": ["274.4 hl ", "250.1 mhl", "250.1 ml", "None of the one mention"]
		},
	
	
		{
			"question": "By how many countries is 80% of the world's wine produced?",
			"correct_answer": "10",
			"wrong_answers": ["8", "6", "14", "12"]
		},
	
	
		{
			"question": "Which pair are not a quality assurance label for Italian wine?",
			"correct_answer": "QbA & QmP",
			"wrong_answers": ["DOC & QmP", "DOC & IGT", "DOCG & ICT", "DOCG & QmP", "IGT & DO"]
		},
	

		{
			"question": "Which is not a france wine region?",
			"correct_answer": "Bretagne",
			"wrong_answers": ["Loire", "Bordeaux", "Bourgogne", "Corse", "Provence", "Champagne", "Alsace"]
		},
	
	
		{
			"question": "Which of this is a wine region and lays in Spain?",
			"correct_answer": "Rioja",
			"wrong_answers": ["Tuscany", "Veneto", "Trentino", "Rheingau"]
		},
	
	
		{
			"question": "Which is not a wine region in Germany?",
			"correct_answer": "Rheinland",
			"wrong_answers": ["Rheingau", "Rheinhessen", "Hessische Bergstraße", "Ahr", "Mittelrhein"]
		},
	
	
		{
			"question": "Which does not fit together?",
			"correct_answer": "Alsace & Schavia",
			"wrong_answers": ["Sicily & Nero d'Avola", "Piedmont & Nebbiolo", "California & Zinfandel", "Austrai & Zweigelt", "Chile & Carmenere"]
		},
	
		{
			"question": "How many of the global wine production is consumed outside of Europe since 2009.?",
			"correct_answer": "40%",
			"wrong_answers": ["10%", "20%", "30%", "50%"]
		},
	
	
		{
			"question": "What is wrong? Wine consumption is",
			"correct_answer": "None of the one mentioned",
			"wrong_answers": ["deacreasing in Spain", "deacreasing in France", "deacreasing in Italy", "deacreasing in the traditional wine countries of southern Europe", "increasing in Australia", "increasing in China"]
		},
	
	
		{
			"question": "What country is not under the 5 most importing wine country?",
			"correct_answer": "Russia",
			"wrong_answers": ["Germany", "United Kingdom", "United States", "France", "None of the one mentioned"]
		},
	
		// Chapter 5 Econometric 
	
		{
			"question": "Which measure of centrality is robust against outliers?",
			"correct_answer": "Median",
			"wrong_answers": ["Mean", "Average", "All of the one mentioned", "None of the one mentioned" ]
		},
	
	
		{
			"question": "Be the coefficient of the variable 3 and its standard error 0.8. What is the t-value?",
			"correct_answer": "3.75",
			"wrong_answers": ["3", "0.8", "3.25", "3.5", "None of the one mentioned" ]
		},
	
	
		// Chapter 6: DEMAND
	
		{
			"question": "What is not a typical law of demand?",
			"correct_answer": "The higher the price of a related complementary good, the higher the quantity demanded.",
			"wrong_answers": ["The higher the price of a good, the lower the quantity demanded (ceteris paribus).", "The higher the price of a related substitute good, the higher the quantity demanded (ceteris paribus).", "The higher the price of a related complementary good, the lower the quantity demanded.", "The higher the income of consumers the higher the quantity demanded (normal good).", "The lower the price, the greater the quantity demanded (ceteris paribus)." ]
		},
	
		{
			"question": "What is not a econometric method that solves the simultaneity problem?",
			"correct_answer": "Logistic regression",
			"wrong_answers": ["Instrumental variable (IV) estimation", "2-stage Least Squares (2SLS) estimation", "All of the one mentioned", "None of the one mentioned" ]
		},
	
		// Chapter 7: 
	
		{
			"question": "Normally hedonic models use revealed preferences of consumers, i.e. no surveys are necessary (as in stated preference models).",
			"correct_answer": "True",
			"wrong_answers": ["False" ]
		},
	
		{
			"question": "What does WTP stand for?",
			"correct_answer": "Willingness to pay",
			"wrong_answers": ["Willingness to participate", "Want to pay", "Want to participate", "None of the one mentioned" ]
		},
	
	
	
		{
			"question": "What is not true?",
			"correct_answer": "Controlling for quality attributes and regional origin, the hedonic analysis confirms that DLG prizes have a big negative impact on prices.",
			"wrong_answers": ["In Germany, wine quality is established by an official testing procedure.", 'DLG administered testing procedure for every German "quality wine” => DLG prizes', "The law categorizes quality wines by their sugar content at harvest => controversial issue.", "Results indicate that special quality attributes and regional effects dominate." ]
		},
	
		{
			"question": "What is true?",
			"correct_answer": "If we knew the hedonic price function and the implicit price of z, we could estimate buyers’ WTP for z, given that this is equal to the marginal rate of substitution between z and the other good c (typically a composite or numéraire good).",
			"wrong_answers": ["If we knew the implicit price of z, we could estimate buyers’ WTP for z, given that this is equal to the marginal rate of substitution between z and the other good c (typically a composite or numéraire good).", "If we knew the hedonic price function, the implicit price of z and c, we could estimate buyers’ WTP for z, given that this is equal to the marginal rate of substitution between z and the other good c (typically a composite or numéraire good).", "If we knew the hedonic price function and the implicit price of z, we could estimate buyers’ WTP for z, given that this is equal to the marginal rate of substitution between z and the other good c (typically a random good).", "If we knew the function of z and the implicit price of z, we could estimate buyers’ WTP for z, given that this is equal to the marginal rate of substitution between z and the other good c (typically a composite or numéraire good)." ]
		},
	
	
		{
			"question": "What is true?",
			"correct_answer": "Buyers with different incomes have different indifference curves, even if they have the same preferences (then U has the same functional form for all buyers).",
			"wrong_answers": ["Buyers with different incomes have the same indifference curves, even if they have the same preferences (then U has the same functional form for all buyers).", "Buyers with the same incomes have different indifference curves, even if they have the same preferences (then U has the same functional form for all buyers).", "Buyers with different incomes have different indifference curves, only if they have the same preferences (then U has the same functional form for all buyers).", "None of the one mentioned" ]
		},
	
	
		// Chapter 8 Reputaiton
	
		{
			"question": "Consumers take present and future quality performance of producers and/or regions into account when assessing reputation.",
			"correct_answer": "False",
			"wrong_answers": ["True", "Depends"]
		},
	
		{
			"question": "Quality signals are imperfect and not fully dispersed across all potential consumers.",
			"correct_answer": "True",
			"wrong_answers": ["False"]
		},
	
	
		// Chapter 9 Reputaiton
	
	]

}